

JACK WELSH

Undergraduate Student at Northumbria University

Website: jwelsh.me

S U M M A RY: Undergraduate BSc Applied Computing student with a FdSc in Networking and Security Technologies. Skills include networking design & security, web programming (experience with MySQL, Java & PHP), and more than three years of experience in retail sales.

EXPERIENCE

GET IN TOUCH



07455126080



e@jwelsh.me

SOCIAL MEDIA



/jack-welsh



@jack.welsh



@JackWelsh15

IKEA Gateshead - Kitchen Planner March 2017 - November 2018

The role of a Kitchen Planner within IKEA required a strong technical knowledge of the products and a consistently creative planning mindset. The role also demanded attention to detail at the highest level. Using IKEA's own planning software and set appointment schedules, I was able to design kitchens within given parameters that meets the customers' criteria. In order to challenge myself further in this role and take on more responsibility, I became an 'order checker'. This involved looking through orders in fine detail before they are processed to ensure there are no errors.

A-Plan Insurance – Senior Insurance Sales Consultant October 2015 - August 2016

During my time at A-Plan insurance, my role was to discuss Insurance Risks with the underwriters as an attempt to build insurer relations and accounts with the A Plan branch. This required a thorough and up-to-date knowledge of the industry as well as a variety of communication techniques. It was also within my responsibilities to advise clients on which Insurers to place themselves with and why. This was carried out via Phone, email and face-to-face interactions.

Be Wiser Insurance - Certified Senior Insurance Sales Consultant March 2014 - April 2015

My role was to confirm, sell and administer insurance policies of all kinds. This required a strong knowledge of insurance as well as an adaptable attitude towards problem solving. The job also meant I had to update the company databases through their intranet via data collection. I regularly exceeded my daily targets, which can only be achieved through dedication, being a strong team player and excellent communication.

EDUCATION

BSc Applied Computing Northumbria University Current (2018-2019)

FdSc Networking & Security **Technologies** Newcastle College Distinction (2016 - 2018)

EDUCATION DETAILS

BSc Applied Computing

Notable Modules: Object-Oriented Web Programming Object-Oriented Modelling & Design Strategic Systems Management Team Project & Professionalism

FdSc Networking & Security Technologies

Notable Modules: LAN/WAN Server Administration Network Security Disaster Recovery Management Work Based Learning

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Alongside my studies at university, I am also an ARMY officer cadet at the Officers Training Corps (OTC). This has allowed me to develop my leadership and people management skills through means of military exercises and drills. Due to the nature of the role, the OTC has also helped to create a very high level of discipline for myself.

SKILLS

- In my studies I regularly use coding languages such as Java and PHP, and also use technologies such as MySQL.
- Excellent presentation and project management skills, with project leading experience.
- Configuring routers and switches on LAN and WAN networks and proficient in routing protocol administration.
- Customer service and retention.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- I thoroughly enjoy travelling and have lived in Germany, Canada and the UK.
- I am a self-taught guitarist and have a handful of experience in local and military performances.
- I enjoy photography whilst travelling and I'm always looking for new places to explore.

REFERENCES

Available on request.